

Tushal N Shah

Product Manager at UNext

- Pangalore, India 4 +91-9986878956 tushalshah@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/tushalshah/

Summary

Quality-driven product manager with several-year background carrying products from conception to production. Excellent technical knowledge and presentation skills. Firm grasp of product composition, structure and applications.

Strengths

- Timeline management
- Vendor management
- Technical acumen
- Product lifecycle management
- Customer training
- Project management
- User story creation
- Customer empathy

- Troubleshooting and QA
- A/B testing
- Rollout coordination
- App development
- Stakeholder relations
- Teamwork and collaboration
- Interpersonal communication
- Technical support

Technical Exposure

ChatGPT, AWS, Digital Ocean, Docker, Salesforce, LambdaTest, Desk365, GitLAB, Wordpress, Graphql, Smart Sheet, Excel, Outlook, Teams, Zoom, LAMP, Eclipse, Postman, HeidiSQL, VSCode, WinSCP, PUTTY, Manual Testing, API Testing, Responsive Testing, MySQL, Postgres SQL, JIRA, Bugzilla, Youtrack, LeadSquare, Virtual Box, VMware Player, Windows, Ubuntu, Cent OS

Projects

EPIC.U

All in One Community Platform

MSGIFY

App to Send Bulk Campaigns / Messages using Sendgrid & Whatsapp

CANVAS

LMS based on RUBY

Websites

Multiple websites based on Wordpress hosted on Kinsta

TARDIS

App to Transfer Teams Recordings to Vimeo automatically using GraphQL

SLCM/ULCM

Salesforce apps to Manage Students Lifecycle

JAWS

In house CRM tool based on PHP

Experience

U-Next Learning Pvt Ltd

Product Manager

Aug 2024 - Present

Bangalore

- Collaborated with senior project manager to outline project objectives.
- Achieved project success by maintaining alignment with specified objectives, schedules, and financial parameters.
- Engaged cross-departmental groups to ensure timely project completion.
- Provided project updates to stakeholders and supervisors
- Worked well independently and also with others

U-Next Learning Pvt Ltd

Apr 2021 - Jul 2024

Assistant Project Manager

Bangalore

- Developed and tracked project milestones to drive on-time and on-budget project delivery.
- Resolved any conflicts that arose during the course of a project by utilizing effective problem-solving skills.
- Created and maintained detailed project documentation including schedules, budgets, change orders and invoices.
- Developed project plans, identified resources and established deadlines.
- Conducted meetings and prepared reports to communicate project status with internal and external stakeholders.

U-Next Learning Pvt Ltd

Aug 2019 - Mar 2021

Quality Manager

Bangalore

- Created test data for validating scenarios based on functional requirements.
- Assisted in troubleshooting customer problems reported through support tickets or other channels.
- Conducted functional, system integration, regression, stress, performance and user acceptance testing.
- Designed test cases based on use cases and business requirements documents.
- Created detailed bug reports with steps to reproduce the issue and worked with developers to resolve them quickly.

Codeveda Pvt Ltd

May 2017 - Jul 2019

Quality Engineer

Bangalore

- Created detailed bug reports with steps to reproduce the issue and worked with developers to resolve them quickly.
- Completed root cause analysis and corrective action planning on materials failures.
- Utilized defect tracking tools to document issues encountered during testing cycles.
- Worked closely with development teams to ensure product quality is maintained throughout the software lifecycle.
- Performed manual testing on mobile apps across various platforms.

Ample Softwares Pvt Ltd

Jan 2015 - Apr 2017

Software Test Engineer

- Tracked software bugs and detailed information regarding findings and resolution techniques in documentation.
- Reviewed business requirements documents to understand the scope of projects and create comprehensive test plans.
- Developed and executed test cases to ensure software functionality, reliability and performance.
- Monitored bug tracking systems for open issues related to software testing efforts.
- Wrote and updated manual test cases for team use, maintaining optimal organization for maximum productivity.

Flight Raja Travels Private Limited

Dec 2009 - Nov 2013

Associate Accounts Executive

Bangalore

- Daily International Flights, IRCTC, Bus, Mobile Top ups, DTH reconciliation
- Reporting on a daily basis average transactions, sales, commission earned and net retention

Standard Chartered Bank

Sep 2007 - Jul 2009

Customer Relationship Manager

Bangalore

- Handle customer inquiries, complaints, billing questions and payment extension/service requests
- Interface daily with internal partners in accounting, operations and consumer affairs divisions

Achievements & Rewards

- Spot Award for contributing new initiatives at UNext Learning Pvt Ltd
- Appreciation Award for handling projects at expected levels at Codeveda Pvt Ltd.
- Multiple Appreciation Awards as well as Employee of the Month at Ample Softwares.
- Earned praise from management for taking the initiative to streamline office operations at Flightraja Travels Pvt Ltd.
- Commitment to quality. Consistently achieved high quality assurance ratings from Standard Chartered Bank.

Education

Indian Institute of Apr 2024

Management, Indore Post Graduation Certification in Product Management

SunRise University Jan 2014

Bachelors in Computer Applications

Rajajinagar Pre-University College Jan 2007

Bachelors in Commerce

Sheshadripuram Pre-University College Jan 2004

II PUC

Carmel High School Jan 2002

STD X

Hobbies and Interests

- Reading Self Improvement/Productivity/Tech Related Articles
- Trying out DIY Projects
- Photography

Languages

English Hindi Kannada Gujarati

References

References available upon request.